<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science</title>
    <link>https://uoit-cs.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://uoit-cs.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Specialization</title>
      <link>https://uoit-cs.github.io/frontpage/frontpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uoit-cs.github.io/frontpage/frontpage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Starting Fall 2017, Computer Science will offer a four-year program with a Data
Science specialization.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graduates of the Data Science specialization will have a solid understanding of
computer science. Additionally, these students will focus on developing
knowledge, skills and tools that will set them up for success in the highly
lucrative and desirable data science job market. Data Science specialization
students will develop problem-solving, critical, analytical, computational and
communication skills that will enable them to turn vast quantities of data into
insight. Specific learning outcomes include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a solid understanding of the theoretical foundation of data science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Achieve a strong command over programming and computational tools to
effectively handle data with volume and complexity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain working knowledge over a range of algorithms, methods and systems for
performing data analysis on real-life datasets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attain a good understanding of the applications of data science across a
variety of domains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn fundamentals of interactive visual analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acquire critical and problem solving skills to extract knowledge and
understanding from large volumes data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Data Science specialization is in response to the urgent need for
individuals capable of turning vast quantities of data into insight. Individuals
with this ability, often called data scientists, are highly sought after in a
variety of industries, including health care, finance and business consultancy.
UOIT’s Computer Science graduates with Data Science specialization will be in
high demand in both government and private sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Courses in the Data Science specialization are completed in addition to the required
courses in the Computer Science major.  Data Science specific courses include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulation and Modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big Data Analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Visualization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Application Development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction to Probability Theory (&lt;em&gt;elective&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mathematical Modeling (&lt;em&gt;elective&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>